[{"question":"A wattmeter is used to measure _____","answers":{"a":"Active Power","b":"Reactive Power","c":"Apparent Power","d":"Any of the above"},"correctAnswer":"a"},
{"question":"A three phase, 400 V load has power factor 0.6 lagging. The two wattmeters read a total input power of 20 kW. The reading of each wattmeter will be","answers":{"a":"17.689 kW, 2.302 kW","b":"14.655 kW, 6.102 kW","c":"11.539 kW, 12.442 kW","d":"9.575 kW, 9.575 kW"},"correctAnswer":"a"},
{"question":"In a two wattmeter power, for all ________ power factors between 0-0.5, one meter shows _______ reading and second wattmeter shows ______ reading.","answers":{"a":"Lagging, positive, positive","b":"Leading, positive, negative","c":"Lagging, positive, negative","d":"Leading, positive, positive"},"correctAnswer":"c"},
{"question":"Two wattmeter method is applicable for balanced as well as unbalanced load.","answers":{"a":"True","b":"False"},"correctAnswer":"a"},
{"question":"Two wattmeter method applicable for three phase, 4 wire system.","answers":{"a":"True","b":"False"},"correctAnswer":"b"},
{"question":"In a 3-phase power measurement by two wattmeter method, both the wattmeters had identical readings. The power factor of the load was","answers":{"a":"Unity","b":"0.8 lagging","c":"0.8 leading","d":"Zero"},"correctAnswer":"a"},
{"question":"In a 3-phase power measurement by two wattmeter method the reading of one of the wattmeter was zero. The power factor of the load must be","answers":{"a":"Unity","b":"0.5","c":"0.3","d":"Zero"},"correctAnswer":"b"},
{"question":"How many coils are there in wattmeter?","answers":{"a":"3","b":"4","c":"1","d":"2"},"correctAnswer":"d"},
{"question":"While measuring power by two wattmeter method, the phase voltage is 3 V whereas the phase current is 0.5A. If the angle between phase current and phase voltage is 30 degrees, the total power consumed by the load will be","answers":{"a":"3.125 W","b":"1.11 W","c":"2.25 W","d":"2.57 W"},"correctAnswer":"c"},
{"question":"The power in an unbalance 3-phases 4-wire circuit can be measured by using a method.","answers":{"a":"4 Wattmeter","b":"3 Wattmeter","c":"2 Wattmeter","d":"1 Wattmeter"},"correctAnswer":"b"}]
